use stable diffusion thanks for watching
this SN semic all right you probably
need some more explanation later in the
video I'll also show you how to create
everything from 3D models to animations
and artifacts so make sure to watch
until getting stable diffusion set up I
used to recommend Google collab but
Google isn't a fan anymore so you might
be tempted to search for other AI image
generators but I still say stable
diffusion is the best choice if you have
a computer with a discrete graphics card
I'd suggest just running stable
diffusion locally installation and usage
are as simple as downloading and running
it I'm not going to dive too deep into
that as I don't want to make the video
too long once you have stable diffusion
running let me briefly explain different
stable diffusion models big update since
last time we now have sdxl and stable
diffusion 3 stable diffusion 3 is newer
but I recommend sticking with sdxl I'll
explain why later I also personally use
comfy UI to run stable diffusion and
I'll include the workflow I used in the
video description now that you got your
stable diffusion model let's talk about
luras Lura or low rank adaptations are
smaller files that act as Concepts or
guidelines for your model to put it
simply if you have a pixel art Laura
your model will focus more on generating
pixel art using Laura's help you get
more consistent desire results you might
be wondering about the difference
between using a different model and
using a Laura here's an analogy think of
your model as an experienced Chef
cooking a specific meal the recipe for
that meal is Laura even if the chef
changes there's still following the same
recipe which means they're not learning
a completely new cooking style just
following the instructions now for the
fun part go to civit ai.com and find the
model and Laura you want for your game
for this example let's generate some
pixel art that's right this is something
I couldn't quite do in my previous AI
video for this we'll be using sdxl 1.0
with a pixel art XL Lura the reason why
we picked sdxl previously is because
simply there are more luras available
for this model by the way using Aur is
as simple as placing the file in a
folder and selecting it in the web
interface the results as you can see are
surprisingly good similar to pixel art
you can pick any other Laura to generate
Sprites exactly how you want for 3D
textures it's pretty similar to what I
explained in the old video you don't
even need Aura just type your prompt and
you'll get your texture one thing to
note is that AI doesn't always make
seamless textures no matter how much you
prompt it to solve this use a procedural
stochastic Shader you can also generate
additional detail maps to enhance the
texture this is all covered in my old
video and my project terminal devlog so
check those videos out if you're
interested for those who don't want to
run stable diffusion locally I recommend
tensor doart as a good alternative and
if you're looking for alternatives to
stable diffusion models I suggest flux
AI which is a new AI that excels at
generating images with text now for the
big question can it create sprad sheets
in my last video AI failed miserably at
this and to be honest it's still not
great but before you click away I found
a workaround that makes Sprite sheets
very usable here's how it works first we
take a 3D humanoid model which can be AI
generated then app ply on animation
which can be AI generated and then
export the animation frame by frame and
for each frame apply a pixelation effect
using AI when you compile all the frames
into a spray sheeet you get a decent
result you might be wondering semic
coder why not just just use a pixelation
effect in why use AI well the AI
effect just looks miles better the good
thing is you don't need a detailed 3D
model or animation because everything
will be pixelated and turned into a lowf
frame rate Sprite sheet so generating
models and animations this way is
totally viable I'll talk more about how
to generate them in a later segment of
the video As for the 3D model generation
there are a few options for
environmental assets like props or
environment I recommend sl. a and meshy
and no I'm not sponsored by them both
offer free tiers where you can generate
an export models I would use sloyd AI
for low poly casual games and Meshi for
more detailed models with high quality
textures Rodin AI is also a good option
it's still in public beta but so far
I've had the best results with it
specifically for digital avatars most of
the times I got better results using
image to 3D model generation rather than
text to image you might also be
interested in rodent diffusion a
generative model for sculpting 3D
avatars but as of this recording it's
not available to the public yet it still
looks very promising
though now about animations this is
where things need a bit more development
the most viable option right now is to
Auto rig your generated 3D character
using mix ammo and then apply mix ammo
animations another option is AI motion
capture which can turn regular videos
into 3D animations for your character
text to animation technology however
still needs more work I'd
say sound effects I think 11 laps is the
best option
here udio generates great ambient music
perfect for game development fun fact
the music in this video is all generated
by Audio play. HT works really well and
looped is also using voice generated by
play. HT and that covers pretty much all
the essential game m you'll need to make
a game before I wrap up I just want to
address that while AI can speed up your
workflow I'd like to tell you to not
rely too heavily on AI it's a tool not a
complete replacement for creativity so
the best would be to mix it with your
own
creativity this has been semic coder I
kind of know how to code
[Music]